Buffalo Baptist Association papers
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Buffalo Baptist Association papers
1836 - 1935
1 box (44 folders; 0.5 linear ft.)
Buffalo Baptist Association (N.Y.)
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Arcade Baptist Church (Arcade, N.Y.); Baptist associations New York (State) Buffalo; Baptists New York (State) Buffalo History; Bethel Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Buffalo Baptist Association (N.Y.); Cazenovia Park Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Cedar Street Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Baptist church buildings New York (State) Buffalo History; Coxhead, Carrie Hope; Delaware Avenue Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Delevan Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); East Aurora Baptist Church (East Aurora, N.Y.); Eden Baptist Church (Eden, N.Y.); Holmes, Elkanah; Fillmore Avenue Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); First Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); First German Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Glenwood Avenue Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Holland Baptist Church (Holland, N.Y.); Hope Chapel (Buffalo, N.Y.); Hunt Avenue Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Indians New York (State) Buffalo; Java Village Baptist Church (Java, N.Y.); Kensington Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Lafayette Avenue Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Maple Street Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Michigan Street Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); North Park Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Missionaries New York (State) Buffalo; Perrysburg Baptist Church (Gowanda, N.Y.); Polish Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Randall Memorial Baptist Church (Williamsville, N.Y.); Second German Baptist Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Sheldon, C.P. (Clesson P.); Springville Baptist Church (Springville, N.Y.); Strykersville Baptist Church (Strykersville, N.Y.); Wales Baptist Church (Wales, N.Y.)
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Collection includes histories of various Baptist Churches and prominent figures involved in the Baptist Church in the Western New York area.
Collection is arranged alphabetically by church name.
- Folder 1: Arcade Baptist Church history by Henry K. Vye
- Folder 2: Baptist beginnings in Western New York by George Whitman
- Folder 3: Bethel Baptist Church Historical sketch
- Folder 4: Buffalo Baptist Association, Constitution and Bylaws
- Folder 5: Historical sketch of Buffalo Baptist Association by George Whitman
- Folder 6: Buffalo Baptist Association, History from 1840 to 1910 by Rev. John Naylor
- Folder 7: Buffalo Baptist Association, Interesting points of local history by Carl Daniel
- Folder 8: Buffalo Baptists Newspaper publicity, 1932-1935, compiled by David Dahlstrom
- Folder 9: Buffalo Baptist Association papers, 1931-1933
- Folder 10: Carrie Hope Coxhead, a tribute to her by Mary Benson Dorland
- Folder 11: History of the Cazenovia Park Baptist Church
- Folder 12: A brief history of the Cedar Street Baptist Church, 1856-1919
- Folder 13: Historical sketch of the Cedar Street Baptist Church, 1859-1910
- Folder 14: Delaware Avenue Baptist Church first fifty years by David Dahlstrom
- Folder 15: Delaware Avenue Baptist Church, ordinations of Robert L. Ryerse & Douglas G. Haring, 1917 and 1928
- Folder 16: Delaware Avenue Baptist Church," The Searchlight" exceprts
- Folder 17: Some recollections of early days of Delaware Avenue Baptist Church by George Benson
- Folder 18: History of Delavan Baptist Avenue Church
- Folder 19: History of the First Baptist Church, East Aurora, N.Y.
- Folder 20: (2) History of the Eden Baptist Church
- Folder 21: Fillmore Avenue Baptist Church
- Folder 22: First Baptist Church of Buffalo (North Pearl and North Sts.)
- Folder 23: Historical sketch of the first German Baptist Church of Buffalo, N.Y.
- Folder 24: History of the II German Baptist Church of Buffalo, N.Y.
- Folder 25: History of the Glenwood Avenue Baptist Church, Buffalo, N.Y.
- Folder 26: Elkanah Holmes and the early Baptist missionaries of Western New York by Geroge Whitman
- Folder 27: Historical sketch of the Baptist Church in Holland, N.Y. by Rev. James M. Bates
- Folder 28: Historical sketch of the Hope Chapel
- Folder 29: Hunt Avenue Baptist Church
- Folder 30: Indians in the Buffalo Baptist Association by Rev. Carl Case
- Folder 31: History of the Java Village Baptist Church, September 1, 1910
- Folder 32: History of the Kensington Avenue Baptist Church
- Folder 33: Lafayette Avenue Baptist Church
- Folder 34: History of the Maple Street Baptist Church
- Folder 35: History of the Michigan Street Baptist Church, March 1836-1908
- Folder 35a: (2) Photocopy of history of the Michigan Street Baptist Church, March 1836-1908
- Folder 36: Brief history of the North Park Baptist Church
- Folder 37: History of the Perrysburg Baptist Church of Gowanda, N.Y.
- Folder 38: Polish Baptist Church
- Folder 39: History of the Randall Memorial Baptist Church by Katherine G. Randall
- Folder 40: Some of the early missionaries of WNY by C.W. Brooks
- Folder 41: History of the Springville Baptist Church
- Folder 42: History of the Strykersville Baptist Church by Amy Barber, 1910
- Folder 43: History of the First Baptist Church in Wales, N.Y
- Folder 44: Rev. Clesson P. Sheldon re: Settlement in Buffalo, 1848